[
    {
        "front": "かいます|",
        "back": "keep (a pet), raise (an animal)",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "はしります|\n[みちを～］ ",
        "back": "run, drive [along a road]",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "みえます||\n[やまが～］ ",
        "back": "[a mountain] can be seen ",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "きこえます||\n［おとが～］ ",
        "back": "[a sound] can be heard ",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "できます||\n［みちが～］ ",
        "back": "[a road] be made, be completed, come into existence ",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "ひらきます|\n［きょうしつを～］ ",
        "back": "set up [a class], open, hold",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "しんぱい [な]",
        "back": "worried, anxious",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "ペット ",
        "back": "pet",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "とり ",
        "back": "bird",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "こえ ",
        "back": "voice",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "なみ ",
        "back": "wave",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "はなび ",
        "back": "fireworks",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "どうぐ \nクリーニング",
        "back": "tool, instrument, equipment (dry) cleaning, laundry",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "いえ ",
        "back": "house, home",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "マンション",
        "back": "condominium, apartment house, blocks of flats",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "キッチン",
        "back": "kitchen",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "～きょうしつ",
        "back": "~class",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "パーティールーム ",
        "back": "party room",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "かた",
        "back": "person (respectful equivalent of ひと)",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "～ご ",
        "back": "after ~ (duration of time)",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "～しか ",
        "back": "only ~ (used with negatives)",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "ほかの ",
        "back": "other",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "はっきり ",
        "back": "clearly",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "かぐ",
        "back": "furniture",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "ほんだな ",
        "back": "bookcase",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "いつか",
        "back": "one day, some day",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "たてます||",
        "back": "build",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "すばらしい ",
        "back": "wonderfull",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "こどもたち ",
        "back": "children",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "だいすき［な］",
        "back": "like very much",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "しゅじんこう ",
        "back": "hero, heroine",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "かたち ",
        "back": "shape",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "ふしぎ ",
        "back": "fantastic, mysterious",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "ポケット",
        "back": "pocket",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "たとえば ",
        "back": "for example",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "つけます||",
        "back": "attach, put on",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "じゆうに ",
        "back": "freely",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "そら ",
        "back": "sky",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "とびます|",
        "back": "fly",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "むかし",
        "back": "old days, ancient times",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "じぶん",
        "back": "oneself",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "しょうらい",
        "back": "future",
        "chapter": 27
    },
    {
        "front": "※ドラえもん",
        "back": "name of a cartoon character",
        "chapter": 27
    }
]